# Feuler Tovar

52 Fletcher St. | North Attleboro, MA 02760 | <a href="mailto:feulermvp@gmail.com">feulermvp@gmail.com</a> (617)407-2750

# **Professional Summary:**

Software Engineer with strong knowledge of Software Development life cycle and Agile methodology. Hands on development with build tools such as Visual C++, Xcode, Eclipse, Maven and Jenkins continuous integration system. Working knowledge of various scripting languages. Individual contributor with strong team player mindset and interpersonal skills, looking to develop into a software development manager in the next 4 years.

### Technical Skills:

C++, Java/J2EE, SVN, GIT, Perl, Bash, Batch, MySQL, Linux, UNIX, MAC, Windows, Selenium Test, PHP, REST, SOAP, HTTP, Jenkins, Apache, Tomcat, Amazon RDS, EC2, VPC, S3, Python, Ruby on Rails (edx.org)

### Experience:

Atlas Travel-Marlborough, MA

Dec.2016 - Present

**Development Systems Engineer** – Travel Management Group

- Develop web applications using Spring, Hibernate, and Java J2EE frameworks
- Maintained and configured Production and Test Server Platforms.
- Developed and updated automated CVS report generators using Java, PHP, Perl, REST, & SOAP APIs.
- Administered Continuous Integration Jenkins instances

### InMusicBrands-Somerville, MA

Aug.2014 - Mar.2016

**Software Release Engineer** – InMusicBrands

- Maintained code repository using SVN and GIT
- Installed and Configured Jenkins Server to manage 7 build nodes
- Maintained Python based scripts for the Build System's backend.
- Distributed builds for cross-team testing using Amazon S3.
- Developed Bash (Unix Shell) Command line Scripts.

#### Feuler Tovar

52 Fletcher St.| North Attleboro, MA 02760 | <a href="mailto:feulermusic@gmail.com">feulermusic@gmail.com</a> (617)407-2750

# InMusicBrands- Somerville, MA Software Engineer – SONiVOX Group

Dec.2012 - Aug.2014

- Wrote and Debugged MAC and Windows code for Virtual Instruments (VST)
- Upgraded VSTi UI framework for Mac and Windows.
- VSTGUI Development for music software plugins and build tools
- Added 64-bit compatibility to 32-bit plugins using C++ and VST SDK
- Added AAX plugin format to legacy and new product lines

## Cakewalk Music Software-Boston, MA Software Engineer

Jan.2009 - Dec.2012

- Lead developer responsible for legacy & joint 3<sup>□</sup> party applications
- Used Microsoft Foundation Class(MFC) libraries, Some STL and C++ to write and update custom user interfaces.
- Improved testing by updating C++ base authorization scheme
- Wrote SoundCloud.Com helper tool using C, HTTP Protocols, and REST APIs.

## Cakewalk Music Software-Boston, MA Software Release Engineer

Jan.2000 - Jan.2009

- Administered code repository using Visual Studio Source Safe, SVN, Mercurial Kiln
- Developed C++ UI features for 3<sup>d</sup> party joint venture products.
- Improved and developed C++ and Perl base build system and scripts
- Managed 6 node build system supporting Visual Studio 2005, 2008 & 2010

# **Block Financial Corporation -** Somerville, MA *Internal Support Engineer* –

Oct.1994 - Jun.1998

- Responsible for compiling and debugging C codes for TaxCut State software.
- Responsible for building master disk for all 'state' versions for distribution.
- Forum Administrator for Block Financial CompuServe CSI/Web forum.
- Responsible for Technical support of Block Financial Web based products.

### Education:

**Boston University**-Boston, MA, Class of 2020 Degree candidate for Computer Science **Air Force Academy Prep School**, Colorado Springs, CO *Class of '92*